# **Tomas Madariaga**

1311 Bonita Ave 94709 Berkeley CA, +1 510 338 2169

www.tomasmadariaga.com - es.linkedin.com/in/tomasmadariaga/en - www.github.com/tomasmax madariaga.tomas@gmail.com

#### **PROFILE**

Full stack Software Engineer, Product Manager, IT consultant with 4+ years working experience in several Start-ups and in a Big B2B consulting company with a multi-cultural background (Europe & USA). Computer Science & Industrial Engineering. Agile Project Management MSc. Big Thinker, Lifelong Learner, Entrepreneur, Business & Result oriented. Ability to learn new programming languages, frameworks and technologies quickly. Willing to create new prototypes, products & solutions. Fluent in English, native Spanish and Basque, medium in French.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Engineer & Product Manager. San Francisco, Moovit

August 2016 - Present

- Work hand in hand with product, engineering and business development team to overhaul <a href="www.moovitapp.com">www.moovitapp.com</a> 5.0
  version release for #1 transit App Worldwide present in 67 Countries, 1200 Cities, with 45+ Million users and \$80 Millions of Investment.
- Front End development (HTML5, JavaScript, Angular2, AWS) for wining SEO, working closely to the UX/UI teams and bring wireframes & design to life.
- Android development. Data mine Moovit user's information and develop data visualization products.
- Serve as product manager to translate new features into technical requirements. App & Web prototyping.

#### Mobile & GIS Full Stack Engineer and Consultant. Spain, Indra

January 2015 - July 2016

- Consultancy and development of a Windows tablet & Android <u>smart mobility solution</u> to speed up maintenance of several utility companies network. ESRI GIS back end with JBOSS server. It currently supports the management of more than one million supply points for EDP, over 9,600 kilometers of distribution network, half a million network elements and 90 maintenance teams.
- Android, Java, .NET Desk & Web development and B2B Mobile & GIS consulting.

## Freelance Project Management Coach. Bilbao, Fondo Formacion Euskadi

May - July 2015

Created a MOOC to increase France & Spain Coworking Space Managers Project Management efficiency, <u>PIRECOW</u> project.

Software Engineer & Project Manager, RoR, HTML5, Phonegap. Bilbao, Grupo Urbegi February 2013 – December 2014

- Managed & developed <u>Council of Bizkaia's loan requests</u> filtering web service, allowing to reduce their response time Ruby on Rails, HTML5, JS and AWS.
- Development of a Crowdfunding platform. Ruby on Rails, HTML5, JS, PayPal, Stripe and AWS.
- Mediapost Group rebranding consultancy, <u>websites</u> design, development & SEO.
- Web Full Stack dev, RoR, HTML5, JS, AngularJS and Heroku & AWS web deployment and server maintenance.

#### Freelance Web Developer & Designer & Marketing

September – December 2013

• Connect a financial social online game with Facebook.

Agile PM Foundation Certification, APMG International

Designed advertisements and marketing strategies to introduce a new IT product in the Spanish market.

Software Engineer Intern - Ruby on Rails, Java. Bilbao, <u>Techabout</u>

October 2011 - July 2012

2015

Meetabout entrepreneurial project Front & Back end development in Ruby on Rails, Java OSGi, HTML5, JS, jQuery.

### **EDUCATION**

Advanced Project Management Postgraduate Degree, University of Barcelona, Spain	2014
PMBOK, PMP, Prince2, Lean Project Management, Six Sigma. Agile methodologies: Agile, Scrum, Kanban	
MSE in Computer Science, GPA: 3.5, University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain	2010 – 2013
MSE in Business Engineering, (Erasmus), Solvay Brussels School, Brussels, Belgium	2012 – 2013
MSE in Industrial Engineering (Business Management), GPA: 3.5, University of Deusto	2010 – 2013
BSc in Computer Science, GPA: 3.2 University of Deusto, Bilbao, Spain	2007 – 2010

# COMPLEMENTARY EDUCATION

Machine Learning Specialization, University of Washington, Coursera	2016
	2046

Big Data Specialization, University of San Diego, Coursera 2016

<u>Programming Mobile Services for Android Handheld Systems: Concurrency</u> by Vanderbilt University on Coursera

<u>Bizkaia Talentia Program</u>, Selected because of my skills and academic record.

	Ingenio: Innovation, Creativity and Entrepreneurship Program, University of Deusto, Bilbao	2011
TECHNICAL SKILLS	Java, C/C++, Ruby on Rails, Node.js, HTML5, JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, EmberJS, Bootstrap, SASS, LESS, CSS3, SEO. Android and Cordova (Phonegap). MVC architecture. Professional experience in Back-end, Front-end, AWS and Herok Proficient with GIT and SVN. TDD. SQL, SQLite, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, AWS DB. AWS Big Data, Tableau, Penta and Rapidminer.	u.
ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE & AWARDS	<u>Coursera's Global Translator Community (GTC) Volunteer</u> , translate subtitles for course lecture videos.  University of Deusto Business IX Forum Employment and Entrepreneurship Business Simulator <u>winner</u> . <u>Ironhack program</u> Ambassador at the University of Deusto, helping founders to publicize it in Bilbao.	2013 2014

**Software Engineering for Software as a Service,** University of California, Berkeley, Coursera

2012